Preliminary Guide to the Research Council Records, 1925 - 1992
Duke University. University Archives
Research Council records 1925 - 1992
Duke University. Research Council.
13 linear feet Extent: 9000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
The Research Council, also called the University Council on Research, was established at Duke University in 1934, to support faculty research by providing professional travel funding, publication subvention, and research grants. Until 1978, it prepared the annual bibliography of faculty publications (no longer published). The Research Council was later renamed the Arts & Sciences Committee on Faculty Research. The Research Council Records include reports, minutes, memoranda, correspondence, summaries, and faculty publications lists (1934-1976), pertaining to research projects and support for Duke University faculty. Materials range in date from 1925 to 1992. English.
UA.25.03.0003
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Research Council Records was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1964-2004.
Historical Note
The Research Council, also called the University Council on Research, was established at Duke University in 1934. The Council supported faculty research by providing professional travel funding, publication subvention, and research grants. Until 1978, it prepared the annual bibliography of faculty publications (no longer published). The Research Council was later renamed the Arts & Sciences Committee on Faculty Research.
Collection Overview
The Research Council Records include reports, minutes, memoranda, correspondence, summaries, and faculty publications lists (1934-1976), pertaining to research projects and support for Duke University faculty.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- Administration; Duke University. Arts & Sciences. Committee on Faculty Research; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University -- Research; Duke University. Research Council; Research grants -- North Carolina
Preliminary Description of the Collection
- Container List
  - Announcements and general information (Box 1)
  - Faculty Summer Fellowships, 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Grant summaries (Box 1)
  - Budgets (Box 1)
  - Fringe benefits (Box 1)
  - Travel policy (Box 1)
  - Faculty publications lists (Box 1)
  - General correspondence (Box 1)
  - Faculty publications lists, 1934-1950 (Box 2)
    Faculty publications lists for 1925-1935 in Box 10.
  - Faculty publications lists, 1940-1960 (Box 3)
  - Publication general information (Box 3)
  - Departmental research statements (Box 4)
  - Minutes, 1950-1954 (Box 4)
  - Memos, 1950-1959 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1961 (Box 5)
  - Grants summaries, 1934-1952 (Box 5)
  - Memos (Box 5)
  - Reports, 1925-1931 (Box 6)
  - Minutes, 1934-1966 with index 1934-1982 (Box 6)
  - Progress reports, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Progress reports, 1986-1992 (Box 7)
  - Minutes, 1971- (Box 7)
  - Reports to the President, prior to 1970 (Box 7)
  - Seed money (Box 7)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 8)
  - Statements of programs and policies (Box 8)
  - Minutes, 1975-1988 (Box 8)
  - Summaries (Box 8)
  - Report to the President, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Reports (Box 9)
  - Social Sciences Subcommittee (Box 9)
  - Summaries, 1953-1970, [4 folders] (Box 9)
  - Faculty publications lists, 1925-1935, [6 folders] (Box 10)
Related Material
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences records.
University Archives, Duke University.